http://www.uscc.com/privacy

Information about to your Enhanced Calling Features - Apple
Information about to your Enhanced Calling Features - Android
Cart
Shopping Cart. You have 0 items.
Shopping Cart. You have
.
Shopping Cart. You have
.
1. INTRODUCTION
United States Cellular Corporation ("UScellular™", "we", "us" or "our") is dedicated to earning your trust by protecting your personal information. This Privacy Statement is designed to simply and transparently inform you about the information we collect, how we use it and with whom we share it.
We encourage you to read our Privacy Statement carefully. It explains:
What information we collect and from whom
How we collect information
How we use collected information
How we share collected information
How we protect collected information
What are the rights for California residents
How to choose how we contact you and how to contact us
How we use cookies (Cookie Policy)
SCOPE
This Privacy Statement explains our practices about collecting, using and sharing information. As used herein, "Affiliate" refers to any of the Telephone and Data Systems, Inc. owned family of companies. "Third Parties" refers to entities we may share information with, and require they maintain appropriate privacy and data security measures consistent with this Privacy Statement when we share your information as described in this Privacy Statement. We use "Service Providers" to refer to agents, vendors, service providers, suppliers, subcontractors, and independent contractors with whom we have a business relationship.
You authorize UScellular to collect your information when you interact with us. When you apply for, access, purchase, or use our products, services, applications and websites ("Services"), you agree to our collection, use and sharing of your information as described in this Privacy Statement. Our Services include wireless services that provide voice, text, and picture messaging; internet access services; data services, such as vehicle and security monitoring; fixed wireless services; websites; and mobile applications.
Some products and services which are branded UScellular or co-branded with a Third Party may have a stand-alone privacy statement. When a different privacy statement applies, UScellular will provide you with an opportunity to review the applicable terms of service and privacy statement.
When you purchase or use products or services not provided by UScellular, you are subject to the privacy statement provided by an independent third party. For example, while using your UScellular device, you may:
Access a Wi-Fi network not provided by UScellular
Download, purchase or use applications not provided by UScellular
Post on social media or use other third party sites
Purchase from an online retailer
UScellular is not responsible for the data practices of those independent third parties.
CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY STATEMENT
UScellular may update our Privacy Statement at any time, at least annually to reflect new legal requirements, changes within our business, or to clarify our practices. Please periodically refer back to this Privacy Statement to learn what changes, if any, have been made based on the effective date posted with the updated Privacy Statement. If we propose to use your information materially different than what was stated in the Privacy Statement at the time we collected it, UScellular will obtain your consent in the appropriate manner, which may include an opt-out mechanism.
Effective: December 4, 2020.
Updates include: Additional information regarding the collection, use and sharing of information about our Family Compass™ Services, and Collection of Information about Children.
ACCESSIBILITY
To make accessibility-related requests or report barriers, please contact us at Dataprivacyprotection@uscellular.com.
2. INFORMATION WE COLLECT
PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT
Personal Information is information that identifies, relates to, describes, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with you. Personal Information does not include anonymous or de-identified information that cannot personally identify you, your accounts or devices.
The following table provides a summary of:
The categories of Personal Information we have collected in the past 12 months;
The categories of sources from which Personal Information was collected;
The business or commercial purpose for which Personal Information was collected; and
The categories of third parties with whom USCC shares Personal Information.
Category
Source(s)
General Business Purpose(s)
Category of Third Parties Shared With
Contact Information and other Personal Identifiers
Directly from you
Information collected from others, including third party data brokers
Auditing Digital Interactions
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Identifying and Repairing Errors
Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Internal Research for Technological and Product Development
Maintaining the Quality, Safety and Integrity of Services
Workforce Management
Our Service Providers
Government authorities or other entities with the legal authority
Third parties with whom you intentionally interact
Customer Proprietary Network Information (“CPNI”)
We collect automatically when you use our services
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Identifying and Repairing Errors
Short-term, Transient Collection and Use
Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Internal research for Technological and Product Development
Maintaining the Quality, Safety and Integrity of Services
Workforce Management
Our Service Providers
Government authorities or other entities with the legal authority
Third parties with whom you intentionally interact
Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law
Directly from you
Third party data brokers and others
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Workforce Management
Our Service Providers
Government authorities or other entities with the legal authority
Credit and Financial Information
Directly from you
Collected from others
Auditing Digital Interactions Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Identifying and Repairing Errors
Short-term, Transient Collection and Use
Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Workforce Management
Our Service Providers
Government authorities or other entities with the legal authority
Commercial Information
Directly from you
Collected from others
We collect automatically when you use our Services
Auditing Digital Interactions
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Identifying and Repairing Errors
Short-term, Transient Collection and Use
Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Internal Research for Technological and Product Development
Maintaining the Quality, Safety and Integrity of Services
Workforce Management
Our Service Providers
Government authorities or other entities with the legal authority
Third parties with whom you intentionally interact
Network and Device Information
We collect automatically when you use our Service
Auditing Digital Interactions
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Identifying and Repairing Errors
Short-term, Transient Collection and Use
Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Internal Research for Technological and Product Development
Maintaining the Quality, Safety and Integrity of Services
Workforce Management
Our Service Providers
Government authorities or other entities with the legal authority
Third parties with whom you intentionally interact
Internet or other similar network activity
Directly from you
We collect automatically
Third party data brokers and others
From cookies
Auditing Digital Interactions
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Identifying and Repairing Errors
Short-term, Transient Collection and Use
Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Internal Research for Technological and Product Development
Maintaining the Quality, Safety and Integrity of Services
Our Service Providers
Government authorities or other entities with the legal authority
Third parties
Location Information
Directly from you
We collect automatically when you use our Service
Auditing Digital Interactions
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Identifying and Repairing Errors
Short-term, Transient Collection and Use
Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Internal Research for Technological and Product Development
Maintaining the Quality, Safety and Integrity of Services
Workforce Management
Our Service Providers
Government authorities or other entities with the legal authority
Third parties with whom you intentionally interact
Sensory and other
Biometric Data
Directly from you
We collect Sensory Data automatically when you use our Service
Biometric identifiers will not be created without your express consent.
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Identifying and Repairing Errors Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Internal Research for Technological and Product Development
Maintaining the Quality, Safety and Integrity of Services
Workforce Management
Our Service Providers
Government authorities or other entities with the legal authority
Cookie Data
We collect automatically
Cookies
Auditing Digital Interactions
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Identifying and Repairing Errors
Short-term, Transient Collection and Use
Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Internal Research for Technological and Product Development
Maintaining the Quality, Safety and Integrity of Services
Our Service Providers
Government authorities or other entities with the legal authority
Third parties with whom you intentionally interact
Independent third parties
Inferences drawn from other Personal Information
Directly from you
We collect automatically
Third party data brokers and others
From cookies
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Identifying and Repairing Errors
Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Internal Research for Technological and Product Development
Maintaining the Quality, Safety and Integrity of Services
Workforce Management
Our Service Providers
Government authorities or other entities with the legal authority
Professional or employment related Information
Directly from you
Collected from third parties
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Workforce Management
Our Service Providers
Government authorities or other entities with the legal authority
Education Information
Directly from you
Collected from third parties
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Workforce Management
Our Service Providers
Government authorities or other entities with the legal authority
TYPES OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU
We may collect the following different types of Personal Information about you, your associated accounts, or your devices based on your use of our Services, as well as your business relationship with us or with our Third Parties:
Personal Identifiers. Personal Identifiers are Personal Information that identifies the person such as name, physical and email addresses, telephone numbers, date of birth, Social Security Numbers, Driver's License Numbers, credit card or financial account information or Customer Proprietary Network Information ("CPNI"). Personal Information does not include anonymous or de-identified information that cannot personally identify you, your accounts or devices.
Customer Proprietary Network Information (“CPNI”). CPNI is a specific type of Personal Information that relates to and includes information that we have about you because of the wireless telecommunication services we provide to you. Please refer to our section on CPNI for more information.
Protected Classification. Federal and State laws identify certain characteristics as protected classifications which may include age (40 years or older), race, ancestry, national origin, citizenship, marital status, gender, veteran or military status.
As a federal contractor, UScellular is required to invite job applicants to voluntarily identify gender and race along with veteran and disability status. Any information provided as part of this process will be kept in a confidential file separate from the employment application, will not be used as a basis in any employment decision, and will not be made available to individuals involved in the interview/employment process.
Credit and Financial Information. Credit and Financial Information are specific types of Personal Information that relate to your financial or commercial relationship with us, including your credit history, credit card numbers, banking information, and payment history for opening and managing your account as well as for billing and collection purposes.
Commercial Information. Commercial Information is information about a consumer’s records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies.
Network and Device Information. Network and Device Information is collected when you use our Services. Certain information such as Advertising IDs and persistent device identifiers may directly or indirectly identify you or your device and may be considered a type of Personal Information. Device identifiers include Electronic Serial Numbers (ESN) and mobile equipment identifiers (MEID) which are static numbers linked to a device. Advertising IDs are randomly generated codes on a mobile device that may be changed by the user. This type of information may help identify the same user across multiple devices or channels. Network and Device Information also may include call records, websites and URLs visited, advertisements clicked, WiFi usage, roaming, browsing history, IP addresses, and device data (battery life, application use, operating system, software configurations). We may collect cookies, web beacons and similar technology. Please refer to our Cookie Policy for more information.
Internet Activity and Cookie Data. Internet Activity, Cookie Data or other electronic network activity information may include browsing history, search history, Network Identifiers such as browsing history, search history, IP addresses, and information regarding a consumer’s interaction with an Internet Web site, application or advertisement.
Location Information. Location Information is collected when you provide it directly to us and when you use our Services. Location Information may include your physical address, zip code, and a physical address associated with an IP address. Mobile device location may be the location of the tower with the associated sector and azimuth that the device is connected to, or the latitude and longitude of a mobile device within a given radius. Certain Services may also collect precise geolocation information in order to provide you with real time location-based services. Certain types of Location Information may be considered Personal Information.
Sensory and other Biometric Data. Sensory and Biometric Information includes electronic, visual and audio information that may be collected when you contact us, or we contact you via our Customer Care services, such as voice recordings or voiceprints, images, other biometric identifiers.
Biometric identifiers will not be collected without your express permission. Please refer to the Biometric Information section for more information.
Inferences. Inferences are information drawn from any of the Personal Information described within this Privacy Statement used to create a profile about a consumer reflecting the consumer’s preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes.
Professional or Employment-Related Information. Professional or Employment Related Information is information related to your employment, including, but not limited to, businesses where you’ve worked, positions that you have held, and professional certifications or licenses.
Education Information. Education Information includes direct identifiers, such as a student's name or identification number, indirect identifiers, such as a student's date of birth, or other information which can be used to identify an individual and may include student records maintained by the educational institution or the completed level of education.
Collection of Information about Children
Our Services, with the exception of our Family Compass TM Service discussed below, are for general audiences and are not designed to be used by children. We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of (13) thirteen, unless we have obtained parental consent through activities such as a marketing promotion.
Family Compass™. If you sign up for our Family Compass™ Service and establish a Family Compass™ account, you may elect to link internet connected device or product(s) (for example, a watch) (“IoT product”) used by a child under the age of 13 to their Family Compass™ account with the verified consent of the parent or guardian of that child.
To establish such consent, the parent or guardian must consent to the collection, use and sharing of the child’s personal information through the Family Compass™ Service which must be provided by establishing a UScellular Family Compass™ or data service account, and consenting to the collection and use of the child’s information on the Family Compass™ Portal, the Family Compass™ mobile application or on the relevant device before using the Family Compass™ Service with an IoT product used by your child.
In order to provide verified consent for a child under the age of 13, the parent or guardian must be a Family Compass™ account holder or be the account holder of a UScellular data service plan for the device connected to the Family Compass™ account (for which they were required to provide a government issued ID to verify identity).
In providing consent to link a child’s IoT product to your Family Compass™ account, you represent that you are a UScellular account holder, are the parent or guardian of the child under the age of 13, and authorize their use of the Family Compass™ Service.
If you do not respond to an invitation to connect to the Family Compass™ account within a reasonable time, UScellular will delete your online contact information from our records.
We collect from the Family Compass™ account holder personal information about children whose IoT products are linked to their Family Compass™ account, including an IoT product identifier.
This information allows us to activate Family Compass™ Services on the child’s IoT product.
We will not require a child to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in Family Compass™, but it is important to recognize that the nature of Family Compass™ is to share location and other related information with others linked on the Family Compass™ account.
Once the Family Compass™ Service is activated on the child’s IoT product, we may collect real-time location of the IoT product through GPS and WiFi tracker functionality.
We use this location information to provide Family Compass™ Service, including sending notifications to you and your other designated users of the Family Compass™ account about the child’s location, including when the child’s IoT product enters or exists an established geographic zone.
We may share location information associated with a child’s IoT product with other users you authorize to receive such information—which includes all other individuals connected through the Family Compass™ account.
We may share a child’s personal information with our service providers to provide customer service, troubleshoot issues with the child’s IoT product or the Family Compass™ Service, or in connection with other business purposes including the Detection and Prevention of Security Incidents and Fraud as described in greater detail in this Policy. One of these service providers that may collect personal information from the IoT device connected to Family Compass™ and serve as another operator on the Family Compass™ Service is Smith Micro, which provides the firmware software development kit for the IoT product.
Smith Micro may be contacted at 5800 Corporate Drive, 5th Floor, Pittsburgh, PA, 1527, privacy@smithmicro.com or 1-412-837-5300.
We do not otherwise disclose or share children’s personal information to any third parties and do not use personal information collected from children’s devices for marketing purposes. The Family Compass™ service does not allow children under 13 years of age to make their personal information publicly available.
Parents and guardians are always in control of the personal information we collect about their child through Family Compass™.
They may review or request deletion of their child’s personal information at any time, and also may revoke their consent and refuse to allow further collection of the child’s personal information.
To exercise these rights, please contact us at UScellular, 8410 W. Bryn Mawr Ave. Chicago, IL 60631-3486 Attn: Sr. Director, Privacy and Legal Affairs, email us at Dyno2KidSmartwatch@uscellular.com or contact us at (888) 944-9400.
For more information about our privacy practices, please review this privacy policy, available at https://www.uscellular.com/privacy
in its entirety.
INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE TO US
You provide information to UScellular when you directly interact with us. When you come into a store, call us, access our website, initiate a web chat, participate in a sponsored program, or take a survey; you may provide information such as your name, mailing address, telephone number or email address. You may provide your reason(s) for interacting with us, answers to surveys, voice recordings, and recordings collected in stores.
When you initiate establishing an account with us, you may provide your date of birth, Social Security Number, Driver's License Number, credit card information, images, and create authentication information such as 4-digit PIN number or security questions and answers. When you apply for a position with UScellular, you may provide your Professional or Employment-Related Information or Education Information, as well as your authorization to collect your consumer report or background information as part of the application process.
INFORMATION WE COLLECT AUTOMATICALLY
We automatically collect your information when you access or use our Services. We may collect information about your activity and use of our Services such as calls, texts and picture messages sent and received including the associated numbers; date, time and call duration; websites, applications, or services accessed; browsing history; clickstream data; referral URLs and pages visited; and search terms.
We may automatically collect data about your device such as your mobile number; Advertising IDs; ESN(s) and MEID(s); operating system, device settings; software configuration; make and model of the device; applications installed on the device; signal strength; IP address; and connection speeds.
We may automatically collect information when you visit our websites, use our mobile applications, or register for our sponsored events.
We may automatically collect information when you directly interact with an associate in a store or call into one of our Customer Care centers. We may record the communication, and any transaction that occurs when you contact us, or when we contact you, via our Customer Care services, online webchat portal, or email.
Cookies. UScellular uses cookies, web beacons, pixels, and other tracking technology (collectively "Cookies") to deliver, monitor and improve our websites, applications or emails and display relevant content. For more details on Cookies, please refer to our Cookie Policy that describes the information we collect through Cookies, how we use it and how you can manage your Cookie Preferences.
INFORMATION COLLECTED FROM OTHERS
We may acquire information about you from credit agencies, financial institutions and other independent third party sources, including third party data brokers. These entities may collect information from varying sources such as public records, government entities, loyalty cards, advertising networks and social media.
The information we collect may include credit reports, consumer reports, criminal records, military records and references, and have information such as gender, age, education level, occupation, marital status, children in household, home value, and categories of interest like reading, music, or sports. We may also obtain information from current UScellular customers through referral programs and may combine it with information we have to contact you, or direct UScellular marketing offers that may be of interest to you.
3. USE
BUSINESS PURPOSE OF COLLECTION AND USE
As explained above, we may use, or disclose the Personal Information we collect for one or more of the following business purposes:
Auditing Digital Interactions
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud
Identifying and Repairing Errors
Short-term, Transient Collection and Use
Performing Services including Supporting Activities
Internal Research for Technological and Product Development
Maintaining the Quality, Safety and Integrity of Services
Workforce Management
Auditing Digital Interactions. We may use information to audit activities related to a current digital interaction with you and concurrent transactions, including, but not limited to, counting ad impressions to unique visitors, verifying positioning and quality of ad impressions, and auditing compliance with this specification and other standards. We may use your location to route calls and data services; provide emergency services; and identify and authenticate you for purchases or access to our Services.
We may also use information collected from Cookies, including location information, to improve our Online Services (as defined in our Cookie Policy), complete transactions you request, make recommendations and deliver advertising or similar content.
Detecting and Preventing Security Incidents and Fraud. We may use information to detect or prevent security incidents, protect against deceptive, fraudulent or other activity, and prosecute the responsible parties. We also may use information to protect our network from fraudulent, abusive or unlawful practices; authenticate individuals; and monitor sales transactions for potential fraud. We may access or disclose your information to respond to legal investigations; protect and defend our legal rights and property; protect the safety and security of customers or members of the public including during emergency circumstances; and comply with the law or legal processes such as court orders and subpoenas. We may also use your information to evaluate internal controls and audits for compliance, including those conducted by our internal and external audit Service Providers.
Identifying and Repairing Errors. We may use information to debug, identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality within our Services, network, products and devices. We may monitor and evaluate internal controls for compliance with service level standards in the network, systems, and devices to identify bugs or errors. We may use your information to respond to inquiries or issues about bugs or errors you may be experiencing.
Short-term, Transient Collection and Use. We may use information for short-term, transient use if the Personal Information is not disclosed to another third party or used to build a profile or otherwise alter an individual consumer’s experience outside the current interaction. We may use information collected from Cookies, including location information, to improve our Online Services (as defined below in our Cookie Policy), complete transactions you request, make recommendations and deliver advertising or similar content. For more information, please refer to our Cookie Policy. We may use your location to route calls and data services; provide emergency services; and identify and authenticate you for purchases or access to our Services.
Performing Services including Support Services. We may use your information to perform and provide you with Services, including, but not limited to, maintaining or servicing accounts, providing customer service, processing or fulfilling orders and transactions, verifying customer information, processing payments, providing financing, providing advertising and marketing services, or providing similar services. For example, we may use your information to determine your eligibility for Services; verify your identity; complete, fulfill, manage, and communicate with you about transactions and Services; establish and maintain your account; request credit reports and measure your credit worthiness and payment risk; and properly bill, collect, and refund for Services. We may use information to route your calls and messages; enforce our Terms and Conditions; respond to account, device, or issues related to Services.
We may use your information to personalize promotions offered to you; market new Services to you based on your interests; tailor content you see in advertisements; administer contests, sweepstakes, promotions, and event sponsorships. We may use your location to route calls and data services; provide emergency services; and identify and authenticate you for purchases or access to our Services. We may also use your mobile device location to provide location-based services.
Internal Research for Technological and Product Development. We may use your information to undertake internal research for testing, research, analysis, technological and product development and demonstration. We may use your information to administer contests, sweepstakes, promotions, and event sponsorships; conduct industry or consumer surveys; and other activities to learn about the effectiveness of our Services, products, devices, networks, applications, and websites.
Maintaining the Quality, Safety and Integrity of Services. We may use your information to undertake activities to verify or maintain the quality or safety of our Services or devices that we own, manufacture, have manufactured for us, or control.
We may use your information to improve, upgrade or enhance our Services or devices that we own, manufacture, have manufactured or control, including but not limited to activities that provide support and security for our website, products, and Services.
Workforce Management. We may use your information to manage and ensure staff optimization, set goals and objectives, maintain employee records and facilitate effective communication among employees. We also may use your information to enhance customer and employee experience by optimizing resources to achieve our business objectives.
Aggregate and De-Identified Information. Aggregated and de-identified information have been changed in a manner that prevents others from identifying you. We may use aggregated or de-identified information to manage, protect and improve our network and Services; develop network work plans; conduct traffic flow analyses; investigate service issues; develop credit and fraud risk models; train our associates; and research new products, services and applications. We also may develop analytical tools and methods to measure the effectiveness of marketing and advertising campaigns; develop promotions and offers; and analyze customers' usage patterns. We also may measure the performance of our Services within a specific geographic area.
4. SHARE
We will not disclose your information outside of UScellular, its Affiliates, or Third Parties other than as described in this Privacy Statement. We may, however, disclose your information to companies affiliated with UScellular or Third Parties (i) to provide the Services you have requested; and (ii) for administrative, analytical, and marketing purposes as described in this Privacy Statement.
We may disclose your Personal Information to the following categories of third party entities as follows:
To our Third Party Service Providers. We may share your information without your consent with our Affiliates, Agents, Partners and Third Parties acting as our Service Providers that perform activities on our behalf, such as billing and collecting for our Services; assisting in operating our network; managing our platforms and websites; fulfilling and distributing orders; providing customer support; setting up customer accounts; fulfillment of event and sweepstake prizes; and promoting and marketing our Services. Third Parties that receive information are prohibited from using the information for any purpose other than those for which they are permitted by law or they have contractually agreed to; and if they are processing your information, they have agreed to appropriate privacy and security provisions for the type of information shared.
To UScellular Agents and Partners. UScellular works with a number of authorized dealers and retailers (“Agents and Partners”) to provide our Services. In addition to the business purposes explained above, if you purchase a device or other equipment, activate your service, or otherwise intentionally interact with one of our Agents and Partners through their websites or store locations, they may request that you provide your Personal Information to complete the transaction or Services. This information may be passed on to us as well as be retained by the Agent or Partner.
To Local, State, or Federal Government Authorities or other business partners for legitimate business purposes. We may share certain information, for purposes permitted by law, without your consent such as to prevent fraud; comply with legal requirements; provide emergency assistance; enforce our Terms of Service and agreements; protect our rights and property, and in the event of the sale of part or all assets or other corporate reorganization; conduct audits; and facilitate the calculation of taxes, fees, or other financial obligations.
To Account Owners and Authorized Contacts. Account Owners are parties who are financially responsible for an account (“Account Owners”). Account Owners may grant specific individuals access to their account(s) who are defined as Authorized Contacts (“Authorized Contacts”). Authorized Contacts may act on the Account Owner’s behalf for specific account activities. For example, Account Contacts may make inquiries regarding the account, receive information about the account, pay the bill, change the service plan and make other changes to the account. Authorized Contacts cannot change the Personal Information of Account Owners or other Authorized Contacts. Account Owners may add, change or remove an Authorized Contact at any time.
Roaming Networks. If you are roaming domestically or internationally on the network of another carrier or WiFi service provider, your wireless telephone number, your location, and the numbers you dial and other information about your usage will be collected, stored and shared by the carrier providing the services. If you are roaming domestically, the privacy policy of the carrier providing your roaming services will apply. If you are roaming internationally, the collection and use of your roaming information may be subject to the regulation and privacy policy applicable in the country in which the carrier is providing services which may be different than the privacy regulations within the United States.
Aggregate or De-Identified Information. We may share with Third Parties information that has been collected about you that has been de-identified or aggregated in a manner that prevents others from identifying you. The de-identified or aggregated information may be used for marketing or other analytical purposes, such as to monitor subscriber network interactions, signal strength, dropped calls, or other customer experiences to evaluate customer experience and identify ways to better manage and improve our Services, and help make advertising more relevant to you. Once your information has been de-identified or aggregated, UScellular does not attempt to re-identify the information. We also prohibit Third Parties from attempting to re-identify the information or allowing downstream users to re-identify the information.
Advertising. As mentioned in our Cookie Policy, UScellular may allow third parties to place Cookies on your device when you access our websites, applications or advertisements and collect the preferences you demonstrate when interacting with them. These third parties may use the collected information to personalize advertising that may be of interest to you when you are on other websites or applications, generate advertising leads, or conduct marketing surveys. UScellular adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance's Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising ("DAA's Self-Regulatory Principles for OBA") by providing you with the ability to opt-out of third party advertising Cookies as explained in our Cookie Policy. To find out more about online behavioral advertising or learn to opt-out of the collection and use of your information, click here.
Your web browser may request advertisements directly from third party advertising network servers which do not have a business relationship with us. These advertisements may place Cookies that can view, edit, or set other third party Cookies in your web browser. UScellular is not responsible for the practices, including the use of Cookies, by third party websites, mobile applications or online services linked to or from UScellular Services or for the content contained therein.
Third Party Applications You Install on Your Device. We have no authority over third party applications that you may install or access on your device. By installing or accessing these applications, you may consent to allowing third parties access to information on your device including your Network and Device Information or Location Information in order to support the application's functionality. The Network and Device Information shared may include Advertising IDs or device identifiers in order to provide more personalized experiences, including for marketing purposes such as delivering interest-based advertising. Third party websites, mobile applications, and online services you are able to access on the Internet are outside the control or limits of this Privacy Statement.
Directory Information. UScellular does not publish or support directories of our customers' wireless phone numbers nor do we make this information available, without your consent, for listing in public directories.
WIRELESS LOCATION INFORMATION
UScellular's network receives and tracks Location Information so that it may route communications, deliver wireless content and properly bill customers for Services. We may use your Location Information when you use our mobile applications and Services to provide location-based services ("LBS"), which are services that rely upon real-time physical, geographical Location Information provided by a device to enable a service to the customer. LBS may include roadside assistance services, fleet management services, or mapping services with turn-by-turn directions.
We may also disclose Location Information to third parties with your consent, or as required by applicable law including but not limited to public safety, fire service or law enforcement officials in emergency situations. We may share Location Information with your consent to third parties which provide advertising, as well entities that provide LBS or mobile applications that track the location of the mobile device using our network with or without our assistance. Once you provide your consent to transfer a mobile device's Location Information from UScellular to the third party that provides the LBS or mobile application, that third party's privacy policy will govern the use of that Location Information. You should understand the risks involved in consenting to the disclosure of a mobile device's Location Information before requesting an LBS or mobile application that collects and uses your Location Information.
UScellular retains Location Information only so long as needed to provide and support location-based services or mobile applications, as required by law, or as necessary for valid business purposes.
UScellular does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of Location Information delivered through its network, and any location-based service or mobile application may be disrupted or fail due to environmental factors and factors affecting satellite usage. UScellular abides by the International Association for the Wireless Telecommunications Industry ("CTIA") Best Practices and Guidelines for Location Based Services which can be found at the CTIA's website at http://www.ctia.org.
5. BIOMETRIC INFORMATION POLICY
Biometric Information means an individual’s voiceprints, facial shape, fingerprint, retina or iris scan, or scan or record of hand or face geometry, or information based on any of the foregoing that is used to identify an individual.
Biometric Information includes biometric identifiers and other information as defined by the Illinois Biometric Information Privacy Act or other Federal, State or local laws (collectively “Biometric Laws”), to the extent they are applicable, regardless of how the Biometric Information is collected, stored, or shared.
Biometric Information does not include writing samples, written signatures, photographs, demographic data, tattoo descriptions, or physical descriptions such as height, weight, hair color, or eye color.
To the extent required by Biometric Laws, we may obtain your consent to collect, store, use, or transmit Biometric Information prior to the collection of such data. UScellular and its Third Party Service Providers may collect, store, use or transmit any Biometric Information for identity verification, fraud protection and continued improvement of fraud detection technology.
We will not sell, lease, or share for valuable consideration Biometric Information that is collected.
RETENTION SCHEDULE
UScellular and its Third Party Service Providers will permanently remove, erase, or delete Biometric Information within a reasonable period of time after the purpose for collecting such information has been fulfilled, or within 3 years of your last interaction with us, whichever occurs first.
Unless, in our sole discretion, we suspect you may engage in fraudulent activities, we will delete your Biometric Information within sixty days after we have verified your identity for fraud protection purposes.
BIOMETRIC INFORMATION STORAGE
UScellular and its Third Party Service Providers use reasonable security measures to store, transmit and protect from unauthorized disclosure the Biometric Information collected. Please refer to Protecting Your Information below for further information.
6. CPNI
Customer Proprietary Network Information ("CPNI") is created by our relationship with you as your telecommunications service provider. CPNI includes the type and quantity of certain telecommunications services you subscribe to and includes details about your calling activities, including call detail information such as the date and time of a call; duration of a call; call-originating and call-terminating phone numbers; and charges for a call.
CPNI does not include your name, address, and phone number or information generated by text messaging, picture messaging or data services (such as internet access or usage and IoT solutions like vehicle or security monitoring).
We may use your CPNI to provision your Services; generate, bill and collect for your Services; respond to your requests; enforce our Terms of Service; and protect against fraudulent use of our network. We may use CPNI to recommend other wireless products and services to you. UScellular also may share your CPNI with its Affiliates and Third Parties to market UScellular Services on our behalf. The CPNI rules permit our use of this information for these purposes provided that we safeguard it from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. We employ reasonable security measures to help ensure that your CPNI is protected from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Use of CPNI is subject to federal laws and regulations.
UScellular is prohibited under the CPNI rules from allowing our Affiliates and agents to use CPNI without your consent for the marketing of Affiliates' and agents' communications-related services to you. Your consent allows them to use CPNI to suggest their communications-related services to you or assist you with other telecommunications needs. Affiliates and agents have the same duties to safeguard your CPNI as we do.
When you become a customer of UScellular and no later than every two years thereafter, a notice will be provided to you explaining your rights about CPNI ("CPNI Notice"). You can expect to receive your CPNI Notice on your bill each month, in a separate mailing, or in a text message with a link to the CPNI Notice if you have prepaid wireless services. You must contact us as described in Managing Your Preferences below and in the CPNI Notice if you do not want to grant consent to our Affiliates or agents to use your CPNI to market their communications-related services to you. We will assume you have provided consent if you do not contact us beginning 30 days after the first time we provide you notice in your bill or in a text message.
7. PROTECTING YOUR INFORMATION
UScellular takes reasonable security safeguards within its overall enterprise security approach based on the Center for Internet Security’s Critical Security Controls to protect against such risks as loss, unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure of information. UScellular uses a variety of commercially reasonable and appropriate safeguards to protect information residing on its systems including, without limitation, server firewalls and physical facility security. These security controls and safeguards take into account the scope of the processing activities, the sensitivity of the information, the size of the entity doing to the processing, and the technical feasibility of the security measures.
We restrict access to information to those who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our Services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations. We also have appropriate practices and procedures designed to protect your information. We train our employees on the proper handling and securing of information which includes reporting potential privacy concerns. We protect the security of your information transmitted through our websites by using software which encrypts certain Personal Information you input or view.
We will not store your Personal Information beyond what is necessary for business purposes, including for internal service evaluation and quality assurance purposes, except as otherwise required by law.
We cannot prevent every unauthorized attempt to access information. If you suspect an issue with access to your information, please contact us by calling 1-888-944-9400.
8. PRIVACY RIGHTS
ACCESSING YOUR INFORMATION
UScellular takes reasonable measures to assure you that the information we collect, use and share is accurate, complete and current. We make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your information to allow you to correct inaccuracies at your request, unless the law or legitimate business reasons require us to keep it. Account Owners and Authorized Contacts who wish to review or change their Personal Information may do so by contacting us.
Account Owners and their Authorized Contacts are required to have their own PIN and security questions/answers for account protection. When Account Owners or their Authorized Contacts contact us via phone, they may be asked to provide their PIN or answer security questions, so that we may authenticate them before we respond to their questions or change their Personal Information. Similarly, Account Owners and their Authorized Contacts may be asked to present a valid government issued photo ID in retail stores for authentication purposes before we respond to their questions or change their Personal Information. Account Owners and Authorized Contacts should not provide account information, their PIN or online password to unauthorized parties.
We are not required to process requests for information that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or may be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. In cases in which we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort.
CONTROLLING UNSOLICITED TEXT MESSAGES AND E-MAIL (“SPAM”)
UScellular is concerned about controlling unsolicited commercial text messages and e-mail or "spam." Although UScellular continues to actively review and implement new technology to help prevent these activities, there is no currently available technology that will permit UScellular to totally prevent the sending and receiving of unsolicited text messages or e-mail. Using junk e-mail tools and being cautious about the sharing of your e-mail address while online may help reduce the amount of unsolicited e-mail you receive. For more information about this and other related topics go to the Federal Trade Commission's website at http://www.onguardonline.gov.
CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS
The California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“CCPA”) provides current California residents with specific rights regarding their Personal Information as defined by the CCPA (“CCPA PI”). UScellular respects the rights of our California resident customers to exercise these rights, including to:
Request categories of or the specific pieces of your CCPA PI which we have collected in the previous 12 months in a readily usable format (Right to Access);
Receive a list of the categories of third parties with which the CCPA PI was disclosed or sold in the previous 12 months (Disclosure of Personal Information);
Request the erasure of your CCPA PI which we have collected, subject to certain exemptions (Right to Deletion);
Opt-out of the sale of CCPA PI (Do not Sell my Personal Information); and
The right to be free from discrimination for exercising your privacy rights.
RIGHT TO ACCESS
You have the right to request that we disclose certain CCPA PI collected about you in the 12 months prior to our receipt of your request. Once we receive your request and verify you as an authorized requestor, we may disclose to you some or all of the following:
The categories of CCPA PI we collected about you.
The categories of sources for the CCPA PI we collected about you.
Our business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling that CCPA PI.
The categories of third parties with whom we share that CCPA PI.
The specific pieces of CCPA PI we collected about you.
If we sold or disclosed your CCPA PI for a business purpose, two separate lists disclosing:
sales, identifying the CCPA PI categories that each category of recipient purchased
disclosures for a business purpose, identifying the CCPA PI categories that each category of recipient obtained.
RIGHT TO DELETION
You have the right to request that we delete and direct any Service Providers that have received that CCPA PI to delete, the CCPA PI about you that we collected and retained, unless an exemption applies. We may deny your deletion request, should the information be necessary for us or our Service Providers to:
Complete the transaction for which we collected the CCPA PI, provide a good or service that you requested, take actions reasonably anticipated within the context of our ongoing business relationship with you, or otherwise perform our contract with you.
Detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, or prosecute those responsible for such activities.
Debug products to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality.
Exercise free speech, ensure the right of another consumer to exercise their free speech rights, or exercise another right provided for by law.
Comply with the California Electronic Communications Privacy Act (Cal. Penal Code § 1546 seq.).
Engage in public or peer-reviewed scientific, historical, or statistical research in the public interest that adheres to all other applicable ethics and privacy laws, when the information's deletion may likely render impossible or seriously impair the research's achievement, if you previously provided informed consent.
Enable solely internal uses that are reasonably aligned with consumer expectations based on your relationship with us.
Comply with a legal obligation.
Make other internal and lawful uses of that information that are compatible with the context in which you provided it.
DO NOT SELL MY PERSONAL INFORMATION
In the preceding twelve (12) months, we may have shared, disclosed, or transferred your CCPA PI collected through Cookies to our third party advertising partners.
If you would like to learn more about the types of Cookies we use to improve our Online Services, please refer to our Cookie Policy.
If you would like to manage your Cookie Preferences or opt-out of the sharing of your CCPA PI collected via Cookies, you can do so here: Do Not Sell My Personal Information.
UScellular does not and will not engage in any other activities to sell or share your CCPA PI to third parties for valuable consideration beyond sharing Cookie data. We do not and will not sell or share CCPA PI for valuable consideration if we have actual knowledge that the consumer is less than 16 years of age, unless we receive affirmative authorization (“opt-in”) from either the consumer between 13 and 16 years of age, or the parent or guardian of a consumer less than 13 years of age.
Shine the Light. California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits California residents to annually request, free of charge, information about the Personal Information (if any) disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. We do not share Personal Information with third parties for their own marketing purposes.
DESIGNATED METHODS FOR SUBMITTING CCPA PRIVACY RIGHTS REQUESTS
You may submit a request to us by contacting us at:
California Resident Portal: California Consumer Rights Center
California Individual Rights Request toll-free number: 1 833 500 0439, beginning January 1, 2020.
You may be required to provide certain information for us to verify your identity before we process your request. We require that you provide authentication information (e.g. Name, Account Number, PIN, Address, and Email) depending on the relationship that you have with us. We will verify your identity based on the information you provide on the Consumer Rights Request Form. Once we verify your identity and validate your request, we will communicate with you to fulfill your request, or explain why we are denying your request in whole or in part. We may not respond to your request or provide you with CCPA PI if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm the CCPA PI relates to you. Making a verifiable consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. We will only use CCPA PI provided in your request to verify your identity or authority to make the request.
Requests for Household Information. There may be some types of Personal Information that can be associated with a household (a group of people living together in a single dwelling).
Requests for access or deletion of household Personal Information must be made by each member of the household.
We will verify each member of the household using the verification criteria explained above. If we are unable to verify the identity of each household member with the degree of certainty required, we will not be able to respond to the request.
Authorized Agents. You may designate an agent to submit requests on your behalf. The agent can be a natural person or a business entity that is registered with the California Secretary of State. Authorized Agents are required to verify your identity by providing us with certain Personal Information as described above, depending on whether you hold an account with us or not and the nature of the information your require, which we will endeavour to match the information submitted to information we maintain about you. Additionally, we will require that you provide us with written confirmation that you have authorized the agent to act on your behalf, and the scope of that authorization. The agent will be required to provide us with proof of the agency relationship, which may be a declaration attesting to the agent’s identity and authorization by you to act on their behalf, signed under penalty of perjury. If the agent is a business entity, it will also need to submit evidence that it is registered and in good standing with the California Secretary of State. Information to identify and verify your agent can be submitted through the same mechanism and at the same time that you submit information to verify your identity. Please note that this subsection does not apply when an agent is authorized to act on your behalf pursuant to a valid power of attorney. Any such requests will be processed in accordance with California law pertaining to powers of attorney.
RIGHT TO NON-DISCRIMINATION
UScellular does not discriminate against you for exercising any of your rights. If you exercise your rights, we will not:
Deny you goods or services;
Charge you different prices or rates for goods or services, including through granting discounts or other benefits, or imposing penalties;
Provide you a different level or quality of goods or services;
Suggest that you may receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services.
However, we may offer you certain financial incentives that can result in different prices, rates, or quality levels. Any permitted financial incentive we offer will reasonably or directly relate to the value of your CCPA PI to us, as determined by UScellular, and contain written terms that describe the program’s material terms. Participation in a financial incentive program requires your prior opt-in consent, and we will provide more information about the nature of the program for any particular financial incentive program at the time it is offered to you.
Maine Privacy Rights
The Act to Protect the Privacy of Online Customer Information (“Maine’s BSP Privacy Act”) regulates the use, disclosure, sale, access and protection of customer personal information by Providers of broadband Internet access service (“BSPs”) that provide service to customers who are physically located and billed for broadband services received in Maine.
UScellular respects the rights of our Maine resident customers to exercise their rights and, when providing broadband Internet access services, will:
Collect, retain, use, disclose, sell and permit access to customer personal information for specific purposes as allowed in the Maine’s BSP Privacy Act without customer approval;
Use, disclose, sell or permit access to customer personal information only with the customer’s prior express, affirmative consent except as allowed under the law, as further explained below; and
Not refuse to serve a customer, or charge a penalty, or offer a discount based on the customer’s decision to provide or not provide consent.
Definitions
“Broadband Internet access service” means a mass-market retail service that provides the ability to transmit data to and receive data from all or substantially all Internet endpoints, such as the ability to access retail websites, or social media sites.
“Customer” means an applicant for or current or former subscriber of broadband internet access service provided in Maine.
“Customer personal information” means
information that personally identifies a customer, including customer’s name, billing information, and demographic data; and
information about a customer’s use of broadband Internet access service such as web browsing history, application usage, device identifiers.
Under Maine’s BSP Privacy Act, UScellular may collect, retain, use, disclose, sell and permit access to Customer personal information without Customer approval for several purposes. Specifically, UScellular may use Customer personal information to provide broadband Internet access services as well as for services necessary to provide the services, including billing and collecting payment for the services, advertising or marketing our communications-related services to the Customer, protecting Customers from fraudulent, abusive or unlawful use or subscription to such services, complying with lawful orders, and providing geolocation information for emergency services.
Unless allowed in Maine’s BSP Privacy Act, UScellular will obtain express, affirmative consent from Customers for any other uses, disclosures, sales or access to Customer personal information.
And, UScellular will not refuse to serve a Customer who does not provide consent or charge a penalty or offer a discount based on the Customer’s decision to grant or withhold consent.
The BSP Privacy Act also allows UScellular to use, disclose, sell or permit access to information it collects pertaining to a Customer that is not Customer personal information, unless the Customer provides written notice directing UScellular not to do so.
Maine Customers may exercise their rights under the BSP Privacy Act by emailing us at Dataprivacyprotection@uscellular.com or writing us at the address listed in the Managing Your Preferences section below.
9. MANAGING YOUR PREFERENCES
You may access and review your information collected by UScellular through your monthly bill or through My Account. To correct or update this information:
Contact us by calling 1-888-944-9400. Current customers may dial *611 on their UScellular handset.
Speak with an associate in a UScellular store.
You may manage your preferences for our website:
To opt-out of the sharing of your Personal Information collected via Cookies, please indicate your preference through our Cookie Preference Center.
You may leverage your web browser to manage or restrict Cookies.
You may opt-out of sharing your CPNI with our Affiliates for marketing purposes by:
Calling our toll-free CPNI Opt-out Line: 1-800-509-6254; please follow the recorded instructions.
TTY users can opt-out by first dialing a telecommunications relay service (TRS) center, via 711, in order to contact a TRS Communications Assistant (CA). Ask the CA to dial 1-800-509-6254 and follow the recorded instructions.
To opt-out of receiving marketing communications from UScellular, contact us by calling 1-888-944-9400. Current customers may dial *611 on their UScellular handset. You may also speak with an associate in a UScellular store.
Questions and comments about this Privacy Statement may be directed to:
UScellular
Attn: Senior Director, Privacy and Legal Affairs
8410 W. Bryn Mawr Ave.
Chicago, IL 60631-3486
Fax: 773-864-3133
10. COOKIE POLICY
UScellular uses cookies, web beacons, pixels, and other tracking technology (collectively "Cookies") to deliver, monitor and improve our websites, applications or emails and display relevant content. This Cookie Policy describes the information we collect through Cookies, how we use it and how you can manage your Cookie Preferences.
This Cookie Policy applies to UScellular websites, emails, and applications (collectively "Online Services"). By continuing to access or use our Online Services, you agree to our use of Cookies. UScellular uses Cookies on our Online Services and any device which interacts with our Online Services will receive them. UScellular also works with Third Parties to place UScellular advertisements on their websites and place Cookies in your browser when you visit their websites.
What Are Cookies?
A Cookie is a small text file sent to and stored on your computer or other internet connected device to identify your browser or store information. A first party Cookie is set up by the website being visited by the user. A third party Cookie is set up by a domain that is not the entity hosting the website. Cookies are widely used to make websites work, work in a more efficient way, and identify and track users.
Web beacons are small graphic images on a web page or an HTML email that works with Cookies to monitor web usage, link web pages to servers, interact with emails, and personalize advertising.
Why Do We Use Cookies?
UScellular and our Third Parties may use Cookies on our Online Services to improve our Services and provide you with the best possible web experience. We may use Cookies in order to identify you; provide relevant, interest-based advertising; remember your preferences; secure your access; know when content has been shown to you; provide aggregated auditing, research, and reporting for advertisers; understand and improve our Online Services; and detect and defend against fraud and other risks. When we send you an email, we may use Cookies to understand if you have accessed the information provided in the email. We may combine information collected through the Cookies with your Personal Information in order to provide you a personalized experience including advertising about products and services you may find of interest. The information we collect from Cookies also may allow us to identify you across devices, such as smartphones, tablets, computers or related browsers.
UScellular may allow third parties to place their Cookies on our websites or within our advertisements. And, your web browser may request advertisements directly from independent third party advertising network servers which do not have a business relationship with us. These advertisements may place Cookies that can view, edit, or set third party Cookies, just as if you had requested a web page from the third party site. UScellular is not responsible for the practices including the use of Cookies, employed by third party websites, mobile applications or online services linked to or from UScellular Services or Online Services, or for the content contained therein.
Third party websites, mobile applications, and online services that you are able to access on the Internet are outside the control or limits of this Privacy Statement.
How Can I Manage My Cookie Preferences?
To provide you with the best possible experience with our Online Services, we use different types of Cookies. We categorize these Cookies into the following types:
Strictly Necessary Cookies
Performance Cookies
Functional Cookies
Targeting/Advertising Cookies
You can learn more about what these Cookies do and opt-out of certain Cookies by managing your Cookie Preferences.
How Can I Stop My Internet Browser From Tracking My Information?
Most browsers accept Cookies by default. Depending upon your computer and mobile devices, you may be able to set your browser to control Cookies on your computer and mobile devices. If you do not want to receive Cookies, you may adjust your browser's settings to reject or delete Cookies. To do so, please follow the instructions provided by your browser, which are usually located within the “Help,” “Tools,” or “Edit” menus. Deleting or rejecting Cookies may impact your ability to effectively interact with our Online Services, third party websites or advertisements or otherwise limit your experience, including your ability to find pricing and availability of products and services in your area. Please note that our website does not respond to browser “Do-Not-Track” signals.
My Account
Cart
setting
store
Magnifing Glass
Chat
